Guide to the Horace Trumbauer Architectural Drawings Collection, 1924 - 1958
University Archives Duke University
- Related Collections
  - Operations and Maintenance Department Records, 1919-1957
    - Frank C. Brown Files, 1919-1941
      - Work Reports, George A. Fuller Construction Company, June 1927; October-November 1927
        - Daily work reports of subcontractors
          - Riggs Distler & Company (electrical and plumbing)
          - International Time Recording Contracting Company (installation of clocks)
          - Union Electric Contracting Company (piping)
          - Charles B. Grant (water lines)
          - Anchor Fireproofing Company (fireproofing)
          - Standard Art Marble & Tile Company (Science Building floor)
          - Moffatt Machinery & Manufacturing Company (rubber tile)
          - V.N. Welamb Company (riser and duct work)
          - D.S. Schaffer Company (patching)
          - R.L. Dresser (laying oak flooring)
          - E.W. Minte Company (flooring, trunk racks in Dormitory 1, painting iron stairways)
    - S.W. Myatt Files, 1928-1957
      - Ackland Museum of Art (proposed) [drawings and blueprints], ca. 1940
      - "Aims of the University" Plaque, ca. 1928-1957
        Correspondence between Trumbauer and S.W. Myatt regarding the construction, wording, punctuation and general design of the plaque; plan and sketch of plaque
      - Administration [Allen] Building Blueprints, 1950-1951
      - Allen Building, Correspondence with Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1950-1954
        General correspondence; Specifications for Excavation and Preparation of Site; Drinking fountains and lavatories; Safe
      - Allen Building, Specifications, 1951
      - Construction Projects, Flowers Residence (Dr. Robert Flowers), Blueprints, 1930-1931
      - Forestry Building, School of (Proposed) Blueprints, 1944-1946
      - Hanes House Blueprints [Proposed Nurses Home], 1940-1950
      - Hospital Refrigeration [blueprints], 1944
      - Hospital Refrigeration Room--Architect, Office of Horace Trumbauer [correspondence], 1944
      - Hospital Refrigeration Room--Specifications, 1944
      - Hospital Services Building--Architect, Office of Horace Trumbauer [correspondence], 1948
      - Indoor Stadium (Proposed), correspondence and plans, 1937
      - Law School--Proposed Buildings, 1930, 1948
      - Library--Proposed Addition [Woman's College and West Campus]
      - Navy Building--Proposed, ca. 1945
      - Pegram Dormitory--Proposed Additions, 1954-1955
        Includes materials lists; general correspondence regarding renovation and expansion
      - [West Campus] Library Addition, 1945-1952
        General specifications--rare books, stacks, and workrooms; Correspondence; Book stack and shelving equipment contract; Flood damage (October 1947); Treasure Room; Closed carrels; Library insurance
      - [West Campus] Library Addition--Blueprints and Specifications
      - Physics Building, Blueprints and Specifications, 1947-1948
      - Proposed Buildings and Expansion Plans, 1936-1949
      - Quadrangle Design--Elevation Drawings
      - Social Sciences Building--Old Physics Building, 1930
      - Social Sciences Building, Proposed Addition, 1945-1946
        Includes general correspondence regarding Dormitories 1 and 5 and the proposed Physics Building
      - Trent Drive Hall, Blueprints and Specifications, 1950
      - Trent Drive Hall, 1950-1953
        General Correspondence between A.C. Lee, William O. Frank; Graduate Student dining facilities; Cost estimates for Graduate Men's Dormitory; Daily work logs, 1950-1951
      - Union Building Alterations--Architect, Office of Horace Trumbauer [correspondence], 1953-1955
      - Union Building Alterations, Blueprints, 1954
      - Union Building Proposed Addition, Blueprints, 1939
      - Union Building Proposed Addition, Blueprint, undated
      - York Chapel, Blueprints, 1928
    - Office of the President Records
      The William Preston Few Records and Papers and the Robert Lee Flowers Records contain scattered correspondence with the Horace Trumbauer firm regarding campus plans and construction projects.
      - William Preston Few Records and Papers, 1814-1971
      - Robert Lee Flowers Records, 1891-1968
    - Biographical Reference Collection
      Contains biographical sketches, clippings, and other materials relating to Horace Trumbauer and Julian Abele.
      - Abele, Julian
      - Trumbauer, Horace
    - Building Specifications, 1927
      Includes detailed written descriptions of building material requirements and work specifications for bidding contractors.
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Buildings of Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
        Refers to East Campus buildings. Includes documents written by Horace Trumbauer modifying the original contract specifications.
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Botany and Zoology Buildings, Chemistry Building, Physics Building, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Nurses' Home, Duke University Hospital, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of dormitories, Group "C," Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace, 1869-1938. Specification of Gymnasium Building and Field House, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Medical School and Hospital, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Nurses' Home, Duke University Hospital, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
      - Trumbauer, Horace and A.C. Lee. Specification of Union Building, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. 1927
Related Collections
Horace Trumbauer Drawings and Plans
Free Library of Philadelphia
Julian Abele Drawings of the Philadelphia Museum of Art
Philadelphia Museum of Art
Trumbauer Collection
The Athenaeum of Philadelphia
Horace Trumbauer architectural drawings
Historical Society of Pennsylvania
Horace Trumbauer Collection
University of Pennsylvania Architectural Archives